ELIZAVETA DRIUKOVA

Moscow, Russia <u>e.driukova@gmail.com</u> +7 (929) 580-13-20



SUMMARY

Motivated technical writer with strong knowledge of APIs and docs-as-code tools. Experienced in creating many forms of content, from developer docs to end-user docs and UX writing.

Skilled in DITA XML, Markdown, Confluence, JIRA, Git, command line, Swagger, RAML, Snaglt, and CAT tools.

EXPERIENCE

Technical Writer, Ozon (e-commerce), Moscow, Russia (full-time)

07/2020 - present

- Documented microservices and application architecture. Gathered information via presentations, meeting records, and one-to-one communication with developers.
- Updated the User Manual for WMS (Warehouse Management System). Communicated with QA
 Testers and Project Managers, tested new features and described them.
- Documented e-gift cards API and marketing tools API with Swagger and RAML.
- Localized (Ru>En) Seller Center UI and Cross-border Seller Help Center.

Tools and technologies: docs-as-code, IntelliJ IDEA, Markdown, RAML, Swagger, Git, GitLab, Snaglt, Figma, CAT tools, Confluence, JIRA

Technical Writer, Yandex (IT company), Moscow, Russia (part-time) Yandex.Browser (all platforms):

04/2020 - 08/2020

- Prepared documentation for Kazakh and Uzbek languages localization.
- Analyzed user requests and added the missing information, changed the structure of some articles, selected and added keywords to get documentation to higher positions in search results. This helped users to find the information they need on their own, and reduced the workload of the support service.
- Proofread and updated existing documentation, followed the style guide while describing new features.

Tools and technologies: docs-as-code, DITA XML, Syntext Serna, Oxygen XML Editor, VS Code, Snaglt, Git, Bitbucket

Knowledge Manager, Sodis Travel Company, Moscow, Russia (full-time)

06/2017 - 07/2020

- Prepared the functional specification of an internal wiki system and after its development migrated the corporate knowledge base on visa and immigration issues from MS Word.
- Communicated with representatives of visa centers and consulates in Russian, English and German in writing and orally to update the knowledge base.
- Analyzed frequent customer requests and prepared responses' templates for sales managers. Customer satisfaction with the speed of communication increased from 60% to 80%.
- Prepared materials and trained Junior Sales Managers to work with visa applications. Applying my strategy reduced the average application processing time by 25%.

EDUCATION

Lomonosov Moscow State University, Moscow, Russia

09/2013 - 06/2017

Bachelor in Philology, with Honors (GPA 1.1 — converted using the modified Bavarian formula)

Major: German & English Languages

University of Tübingen, Tübingen, Germany

04/2016 - 07/2016

Exchange semester, Erasmus+ Scholarship

Major: German studies

SKILLS

Languages: Computer:

Russian (native) Microsoft Office Git RAML Snaglt English (proficient: IELTS Academic 7.5) Confluence Markdown Swagger Figma

German (proficient: DSH-3 Certificate) JIRA DITA XML

Soft skills: attention to detail, ability to multitask, self-learning